Guide to the Hammond Film Script Collection ca. 1935-1996 MSS.076 MSS.076
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series E: Gift of Marc Maurette
  - Ali Baba et les Quarante Voleurs (2 of 2) - Becker, Jacques (also Box 15), undated; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Antoine et Antoinette -- Becker, Jacques (also Box 16), 1946; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - La Belle Que Viola (1 of 3) -- [none], undated; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - La Belle Que Viola (2 of 3) -- [none], undated; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - La Belle Que Viola (3 of 3) -- [none], undated; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Les Enfants du Paradis -- Carné, Marcel (also Box 23), undated; 31142040615885 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - L'Eternal Retour -- Delannoy, Jean (also Box 24 & 50), undated; 31142040615885 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Falbalas (1 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615885 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Falbalas (2 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615885 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Les Gauloises Bleues -- Cournot, Michel, undated; 31142040615885 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Goupi Main-Rouge (1 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Goupi Main-Rouge (2 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - The Immortal Story (final shooting script) -- Welles, Orson, 1967; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - The Immortal Story (scenario a jour) - Welles, Orson, undated; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Shogun (TV) (1 of 4) -- Bercovici, Eric (adaptation), 1979; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Shogun (TV) (2 of 4) -- Bercovici, Eric, 1979; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Shogun (TV) (3 of 4) -- Bercovici, Eric, 1979; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Shogun (TV) (4 of 4) -- Bercovici, Eric, 1979; 31142040615893 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Dede -- Benoit, Jean-Louis, undated; 31142040615901 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Une Femme Seul -- Astruc, Alexandra, 1960; 31142040615901 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - J'ai tue Raspoutine (1 of 2) -- Hossein, Robert, 1966-1976; 31142040615901 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - J'ai tue Raspoutine (2 of 2) -- Hossein, Robert, undated; 31142040615901 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Madame de __ -- Ophuls, Max (also Box 30), 1953; 31142040615901 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Maitre après Dieu - Daquin, Louis, undated; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - La Nuit de Varennes - Scola, Ettore, undated; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - La Nuit de Varennes (original) -- Scola, Ettore, undated; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - La Promesse de l'Aube -- Dassin, Jules, 1969-1970; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Sur un arbre perche (1 of 2) - Korber, Serge, undated; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Sur un arbre perche (2 of 2) -- Korber, Serge, undated; 31142040615919 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Dernier Atout (1 of 2) -- Becker, Jacques, undated; 31142040615927 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Dernier Atout (2 of 2) -- Becker, Jacques, undated; 31142040615927 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - La Lune dans le Caniveau -- Beineix, Jean-Jacques, undated; 31142040615927 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - La Lune dans le Caniveau (cover) -- Beineix, Jean-Jacques, undated; 31142040615927 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Premier Bal -- Jaque, Christian, undated; 31142040615927 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - The Lady in the Car -- Harris, Richard, 1969; 31142040615935 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - The Sandpiper -- Trumbo, Dalton, 1964; 31142040615935 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Two for the Road -- Raphael, Frederic, 1964; 31142040615935 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Dames Gallantes (1 of 2) -- Tacchella, Jean-Charles, 1990; 31142040615943 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Dames Gallantes (2 of 2) -- Tacchella, Jean-Charles, 1990; 31142040615943 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Il ya longtemps que je t'aime (1 of 3) - Tacchella, Jean-Charles, undated; 31142040615943 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Il ya longtemps que je t'aime (2 of 3) - Tacchella, Jean-Charles, undated; 31142040615943 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Il ya longtemps que je t'aime (3 of 3) - Tacchella, Jean-Charles, undated; 31142040615943 (Box 69, Folder 5)
- Series F: Plays, Screenplays and Scripts of Richard Maibaum
  Various plays, screenplays and scripts written by Richard Maibaum.
  - Appennine Grape, undated; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Birthright [photocopy] c.1, 1933; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Birthright [photocopy] c.2, undated; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Fearful Decision (aka Ransom) [no script - closed], 1954; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Goldfinger, 1963; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Middletown Mural, circa 1939; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - A Moral Entertainment, circa 1935; 31142040615976 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - The Paradise Question, undated; 31142040615984 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Ransom, undated; 31142040615984 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Ransom, 1963; 31142040615984 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - See My Lawyer c.1, 1939; 31142040615984 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - See My Lawyer c.2, 1939; 31142040615984 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Short Plays: (Callahan's Courage, Trueblue Tommie, Something for Art, Catch as Catch Can, After School, Heart Line, The Light Fantastic, Detached Duty, Champagne for Two), undated; 31142040615992 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Singing Acres, 1933; 31142040615992 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Singing Acres, 1990; 31142040615992 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Speaking of Writing: Lectures & Presentations, 1991; 31142040615992 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Sweet Mystery of Life, 1934; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Sword in the Scales, 1931; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Thunderball, 1964; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - The Tree, 1931; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - The Tree, 1990; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - The Lilac Bush - Maibaum, Matthew, 1990; 31142040616008 (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Series G: Microfilm Negatives of Film Scripts
  Various scripts in microfilm format. Director's name (if provided) is listed after name of film.
  - L'Aigle a Deux Tetes -- Cocteau, Jean, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Amants des Cinq Jours -- de Broca, Philippe, undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Le Banquet des Fraudeurs -- Storck, Henri, undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Celui Qui Doit Mourir -- Dassin, Jacques, undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Les Dernieres Vacances -- Leenhardt, Roger, undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Les Dernieres Vacances (dialogues) -- Leenhardt, Roger, undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Le Diable au Corps -- Autant-Lara, Claude, undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Dieu a Besoin des Hommes -- Delannoy, Jean, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Les Espions (1 of 2) -- Clouzot, Henri-George, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Les Espions (2 of 2) -- Clouzot, Henri-George, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Eternal Retour -- Delannoy, Jean, undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Hiroshima mon Amour -- Resnais, Alain, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Jericho -- Calef, Henri, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - La Marie du Port (dialogues) -- [none], undated (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Les Mauvaises Rencontres -- Astruc, Alexandre, undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Nous Sommes tous des Assassins -- Cayatte, Andre, undated (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - La Nuit est Mon Royaume -- Lacombe, Georges, undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Pension Mimosas -- Feyder, Jacques, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Quai des Brumes -- Carne, Marcel, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Remorques -- Gremillon, Jean, undated (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Ruy Blas -- Billon, Pierre, undated (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Symphonie Pastorale -- Delannoy, Jean, undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Therese Raquin -- Carne, Marcel, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Les Visiteurs du Soir -- Carne, Marcel, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified film, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified film, undated (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Los Olvidados - Luis Bunuel (Spanish), 1950 (Box 80, Folder 3)
- Accretions. 1996 - Series A: French Film Scripts
  - Subseries 7: Various Directors
    - La Belle Verte (c.1) -- Serreau, Coline, undated (Box 1996.1, Folder 1)
      General
      Offsite barcode: 31142042240138
    - La Belle Verte (c.2) -- Serreau, Coline, undated (Box 1996.1, Folder 2)
    - Capitaine Conan -- Tavernier, Bertrand, 1995 (Box 1996.1, Folder 3)
    - La Drole D'Epreuve pour Nestor Burma -- Malet, Leo, 1996 (Box 1996.1, Folder 4)
    - Une Femme Traquee -- Rullier, Chirstian, 1995 (Box 1996.1, Folder 5)
    - Jour et Nuit -- Uytterhoeven, Pierre, 1992 (Box 1996.1, Folder 6)
    - La Mic Mac Moche au Boul' Mich -- Malet, Leo, 1992 (Box 1996.2, Folder 1)
      Offsite barcode: 31142042240146
    - Nelly et Mr. Arnaud -- Sautet, Claude, 1994 (Box 1996.2, Folder 2)
    - La Les Palmes de M. Schutz -- Pinoteau, Claude, 1996 (Box 1996.2, Folder 3)
    - La A Qui Profile Le Crime? -- Alexandre, Michel, 1996 (Box 1996.2, Folder 4)
    - La Le Soleil Nait Derriere Le Louvre -- Malet, Leo, 1991 (Box 1996.2, Folder 5)
    - Les Trois couleurs: Blanc -- Kieslowski, Krzysztof, 1992 (Box 1996.3, Folder 1)
      Offsite barcode: 31142042240153
    - Les Trois couleurs: Bleu -- Kieslowski, Krzysztof, undated (Box 1996.3, Folder 2)
    - La Zeide ou Le Miel Amer - Grumberg, Jean-Claude, undated (Box 1996.3, Folder 3)
- Accretions. 1997-1998 - Series A: French Film Scripts
  - Subseries 7: Various Directors
    - Le Bal des Casse-Pieds (production notes), undated (Box 1997.1, Folder 1)
      Offsite barcode: 31142042240161
    - La Ceremonie -- Chabrol, Claude, 1995 (Box 1997.1, Folder 2)
    - Ca commence aujourd'hui - Taverner, Bertrand, 1998 (Box 1997.1, Folder 3)
    - Le Cousin - Corneau, Alain, 1997 (Box 1997.1, Folder 4)
    - L'Enfer - Chabrol, Claude, 1993 (Box 1997.1, Folder 5)
    - En mai, fais ce qu'il et plait - Grange, Pierre, 1994 (Box 1997.2, Folder 1)
      Offsite barcode: 31142042240179
    - Montparnasse Pondichery - Yves, Robert, undated (Box 1997.2, Folder 2)
    - Place Vendome - Garcia, Nicole, 1997 (Box 1997.2, Folder 3)
    - Ruy Blas - Billon, Pierre/ Cocteau, Jean, undated (Box 1997.2, Folder 4)
    - Les Trois couleurs: Rouge -- Kieslowski, Krzysztof, 1993 (Box 1997.2, Folder 5)
    - La Vouiure - Marcel, Ayme, undated (Box 1997.2, Folder 6)